Here's to the fools who dream.
La La Land is a comedy, drama, romance film directed by Damien Chazelle.
Mia, an aspiring actress, serves lattes to movie stars in between auditions and Sebastian, a jazz musician, scrapes by playing cocktail party gigs in dingy bars, but as success mounts they
are faced with decisions that begin to fray the fragile fabric of their love affair, and the dreams they worked so hard to maintain in each other threaten to rip them apart.
Sebastian, played by Ryan Gosling.
Mia, played by Emma Stone.
Keith, played by John Legend.
Laura, played by Rosemarie DeWitt.
Greg, played by Finn Wittrock.
Tracy, played by Callie Hernandez.
La La Land is a 2016 American musical romantic comedy-drama
film written and directed by Damien Chazelle.
It stars Ryan Gosling and Emma Stone as a struggling jazz pianist and an aspiring
actress who meet and fall in love while pursuing their dreams in Los Angeles.
The supporting cast includes John Legend,
Rosemarie DeWitt, Finn Wittrock, and J.
Having been fond of musicals during his time as a drummer, Chazelle first conceptualized the
film alongside Justin Hurwitz while attending Harvard University together.
After moving to Los Angeles in 2010, Chazelle penned the script but did not find a
studio willing to finance the production without changes to his design.
After the success of his film Whiplash (2014), the
project was picked up by Summit Entertainment.
Miles Teller and Emma Watson were originally in talks to star, but
after both dropped out, Gosling and Stone were cast.
Filming took place in Los Angeles between August and September 2015, with the film's score composed by Hurwitz, who also
wrote the film's songs with lyricists Benj Pasek and Justin Paul and the dance choreography by Mandy Moore.
La La Land premiered at the 73rd Venice International Film Festival on August 31, 2016, and
was released theatrically in the United States on December 9, by Lionsgate.
The film emerged as a major commercial success, grossing $472 million worldwide on a budget of $30 million, and received widespread critical acclaim, particularly for
Chazelle's direction and screenplay, the performances of Gosling and Stone, the score, musical numbers, cinematography, visual style, costumes and production design.
It went on to receive numerous accolades, including winning a record seven awards at the 74th Golden Globe Awards and
received eleven nominations at the 70th British Academy Film Awards, winning five, including Best Film.
The film also received a record-tying fourteen nominations at the 89th Academy Awards,
winning in six categories including Best Director and Best Actress (Stone).
Its loss in the Best Picture category (to Moonlight) made it the
most-nominated film at the Oscars to lose Best Picture.
At age 32, Chazelle became the youngest winner of Best Director.
It has since been regarded as one of the best films of the 2010s and the 21st
century, and as one of the best musical films of all time.
As of February 2023, a stage musical adaptation is in the works.
The film explores themes of dancing, dance, jazz, musical, ambition.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.